The infinite universe.
Within the twinkling lights of these
countless stars, there are many forms of life.
Love...
Hope...
Ambition...
War...
Despite housing all of them, the universe continues to exist endlessly in silence.
Because it is so vast, the universe sometimes leads us to coincidences that can only be called miracles.
Don't you think so, ladies and
gentlemen of the Bolar Federation ?
As I've explained repeatedly, Planet Galman has an
ideal environment for the survival of the people of Garmillas.
It's a miraculous match.
No matter how vast the universe is, there’s sure
to be no other planet that will fit the criteria so well.
That's because the people Galman and
Garmillas are siblings that share common roots.
There's a theory that this planet
could be the origin of the Garmillan people...
...but let's leave the past out of this for now.
For Bolar, this place is one of many resource planets located in the middle of nowhere.
I believe your loss will be minimal.
In exchange, Garmillas will forge an alliance with Bolar, and we'll do our best to help you expand.
I'm left begging for your help...
...in order to save the people of Garmillas,
who are on the brink of extinction.
Please...
The Bolar Federation's Permanent
Administration is indeed generous.
We'll have mercy on Garmillas.
Desler, pick up the choker.
"Alliance?"
How preposterous.
You'll work as Bolar's hands and feet until...
You'd better not be thinking of anything foolish !
Your ship is surrounded by our fleet !
You might be thinking of a surprise attack with your famed
Desler Cannon in case this negotiation breaks down...
...but we'll sink your ship the
moment you start charging energy !
Now, King of Garmillas, it's your move.
Let's forget about your rude display.
The choker...pick it up.
Stop.
Don't do it, Keel.
But...
Gal. (5)
Ji. (4)
Nel. (3)
Beo. (2)
Al. (1)
Zeo. (0)
What happened ?!
I don't know !
All communications just went down !
What did you do, Desler ?!
Let's break through. Go !
Launch fighters !
Our job is done.
Let's enjoy the fireworks.
Poor Bolar. Times have changed.
Desler, how dare you...
Damn animals...
Governor Burroughs !
So, this controller activates the poison
injection of the chokers. How ridiculous.
Brothers, the time of
endurance and obedience is over.
The history that lies ahead will be made by people
with blue blood and blue skin, working hand in hand.
You deserve nothing but fear.
This is the first step
to nation-wide liberation.
Let's go, Keel.
He deserves to be the king...
...a true king who unites the
people of Galman and Garmillas.
It all starts now.
Planet Galman was liberated
through your hard work.
Leaving our dying Planet Garmillas behind will mark the start for our grand plan of migrating our entire population to Planet Galman.
Our fleet will temporarily leave this
place in order to assist the emigration.
I'll leave the Dietz Fleet, dispatched from
the home planet, to guard Planet Galman.
Desler Fleet, set course for Planet Garmillas.
Bolar will most likely come back for it.
I'm sure Dietz will hold out.
It's strange...
...finding a planet like this after
only two years of wandering.
That moon looks almost like...
I forgot to tell you...
When you find a new planet,
please plant some maleidel flowers.
Mother loved them.
I'll look for a planet with it.
That way, I'll know which.
I hope to see you on our
new home planet someday.
Ranhalt, I can finally fulfill my promise.
Those were his last words to you, which were discovered in Yamato's data bank after it had made it home.
Earth still glows blue because he protected it.
Führer Desler, where are you right now ?
I hope this message reaches you.
That lad from the Yamato...
Yamato !
Yamato...
December 31st, 2203
Space Battleship Yamato returns from a higher dimension.
Cdr Kodai Susumu and Cdr Mori Yuki are rescued successfully.
Yamato
Space Battleship
A New Voyage
All right, one two...
Supply Ship Asuka
Battle Carrier Hyuga
All right, one two...
Of all things.
Water training for a space ship ?
It's nonsensical !
It's so yesterday !
Stay sharp ! You guys are the
symbol of the reconstruction of Earth.
One for all, all for one !
Publicity stunt, huh ?
What's wrong ?
Oh, my butt...
Skinned your ass again ?
Alright...
Official post-modification operations are complete.
The Yamato will rejoin the fleet tomorrow morning at 0600.
It's time for Defense Fleet 65 to depart, isn't it ?
Hyuga is the key to air power.
Asuka is in charge of supply and defense.
I expect you two to do your
job well as captains of those ships.
Aye, sir.
Miss Mori, how do you feel
about your role as a captain ?
The ship's performance is more than
enough, and my crew is very capable.
I'm learning everything I can, so
I won't be the only uncertain factor.
You might have some doubts about your triple bump promotion, but I hold your skills in high regard.
I want you to do a good
job supporting the Yamato.
Yes, sir.
By the way, have you had a chance
to see the captain of the Yamato ?
No, not recently.
I see. That's understandable,
given how eager the press is.
It's good that Garmillas has found a place to migrate to,
but the mood on Earth is not as pleasant as it seems.
Many people are worried...
...that we might be caught in a war again.
That's why public attention to this
delegation is very high these days.
Some people make fun of you, calling you a publicity fleet, but I know I can rely on you when needed.
We must avoid any situations where those kids have to be sent to the battlefield.
Those will be your assignments.
Boarding time is 0600 tomorrow morning.
This six month training voyage won't be easy.
Make sure you enjoy yourselves tonight.
Dismissed !
My god, the Yamato, and I'll
be in the engine department.
Your dream's come true, huh ?
Yeah, finally.
Those guys represent the
publicity fleet's splendid reputation.
The son of the Yamato's deceased
chief engineer is assigned to the Yamato.
How emotional.
It can't be helped.
People love that type of tear-jerker.
It doesn't matter who his father is !
He works hard because it's his
dream to be on board the Yamato.
That's the same for all of us.
If your father was a Yamato crewman, you could have been assigned to a position that'd stand out more.
Bando, don't.
How dare you ?!
Not again !
Bando, stop !
Stay out of this, Tasuke !
Bando, that's enough !
Wanna know about my father ?!
He was killed on board the Achilles !
You think that's lesser than the Yamato ?!
Are you nuts ?!
Stuff like that...
You want to be thrown out for
causing problems before you leave ?
But...
I can't accept the fact that he got this
assignment without having any real skills !
They're so spirited, aren't they ?
If you have any complaints, I'll listen.
Ex...excuse us !
It's tough on the Yamato.
You'd better be prepared.
Aye, sir !
What're you guys doing ?
So, he's Tokugawa's son, eh ?
I don't like this mood.
It's so tense.
I can understand their feelings.
A lot has happened since the war with Gatlantis.
True.
I guess one voyage should help them grow up.
Right.
By the way, how is Captain Kodai ?
He shoved all his chores on me and left.
He went through a lot,
so he's probably "there.”
I’m departing tomorrow.
We're heading for Garmillas and Iscandar.
It's the route you and I took six years ago.
But everything has changed...
...including the Earth and me as a person.
Captain Okita, am I...
Yuki...
I knew you'd be here.
Is it okay for you to be here ?
You know tomorrow...
How about you, Kodai ?
You're not okay.
That's why you came here.
Yuki...
How many months has it
been since we were alone together ?
We could be photographed even now.
It can't be helped. After all, we're the
most expensive couple in the world.
The Time Fault is gone.
It had supported our post-war economy
and military strength, but Earth abandoned it.
I'm responsible for that because
I tried to stay in the higher dimension.
Kodai...
I know. It was a decision made by
everyone on Earth, and I'm grateful.
But I have to bear the responsibility for the
cost Earth had to pay for the rest of my life.
Can you really ?
Can one person really shoulder all
responsibility for the entire human race ?
Who are you ?
It's the moon.
Looks like it's been restored quite a bit.
Yamato...?
Oh, it's the Ginga.
What ? Not here ?
"Given recent developments of interstellar relationships, any demonstration of technological exchange with Garmillas should be discouraged.”
That's the brass's decision.
So the technology licensing itself is cancelled ?
No. The skills you've gained
on Garmillas are irreplaceable.
The experiment will be carried out on
schedule outside the Solar System.
Another group is waiting for you just for that.
Another...?
Defense Fleet 65.
The flagship is the Yamato.
Yamato ?!
That's how I ended up going
aboard the Yamato tomorrow.
The experiment will be
conducted on the Yamato.
Mutiny ?
Then why someone like him ?
The fallout from his betrayal
led him to migrate to Garmillas…
...on top of that, he became
an expert in military secrets.
And he's bringing it to Earth ?
Maybe it's a reward for his
contribution to Garmillas's migration policy.
Yamato, of all places,
will be like hell for him.
Yeah, I'm alright.
It's a tough time for Garmillas, but you
don't have to worry about anything.
Did you know ?
When you feel the worst, something
wonderful is right around the corner.
Planet Garmillas of the Magellanic Cloud
Your dad is doing his best, so hang in there.
The evacuation ship will depart as
scheduled Eastern Standard Time.
First class citizens...
Guys, hurry up, or we'll miss the ship.
Can you wait just a bit, big brother Oddo ?
Progress of evacuation is only 30%.
We're behind schedule.
Prepare for the announcement.
The core's meltdown is
increasing at an accelerated rate.
It’s no longer a matter
of 50 years into the future.
5 years...
No, inform the people that there will be
a catastrophic meltdown in 5 months.
But that might....
That's the only way to save
as many people as we can !
But President Hiss, I'm afraid...
Is the life of our planet really going to end ?
Planet Iscandar: Imperial Capital Isk San Aria
Planet Galman is still under Bolar control.
It could be a battlefield by the
time the evacuation fleet arrives.
In the worst case scenario,
Iscandar might have to be a temporary shelter.
So the dispute over Planet Galman
has escalated that much...
The more he tries to redeem himself, the more he sins.
Toru, what are you doing ?
I'll be late for the assembly.
Domon...Domon...
Domon Hightech ?
It was affiliated with the military and manufactured parts used at a factory in the Time Fault.
Domon Ryusuke is the sole son of the company president, and
he's been assigned to the combat department on the Yamato.
Domon Hightech went out of business because of the disappearance of the Time Fault.
Company President Domon Ryuzo...
...committed suicide ?!
It was supposed to be an accident,
a possible suspected suicide.
His son'll be on the Yamato...?
Look, it's the Yamato.
Domon Ryusuke wouldn't have been assigned to the Yamato because of an incident like this.
The disappearance of the Time
Fault is due to the Yamato's...
Oh, no !
Yamato...
A Galactic War is About to Break Out!    Assemble the Yamato Fleet!!
Episode 1
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Yasuo Nanbu:
Yoshikazu Aihara:
Kenichiro Ohta:
Heikuro Todo:
Saki Todo:
Megumi Kanzaki:
Mina Ichinose:
Urara Kusakabe:
Ryusuke Domon:
Tasuke Tokugawa:
Heiji Bando:
Miyako Kyozuka:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Toru Hoshina:
Yuria Hoshina:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Kenji Akabane
Kazuto Kokubu
Yuki Chiba
Toshihiko Kojima
Ayahi Takagaki
Megumi Hayashibara
Tomoyo Kurosawa
Arisa Komiya
Tasuku Hatanaka
Nobuhiko Okamoto
Wataru Hatano
Tomo Muranaka
Ryuichi Kijima
Motoki Takagi
Aya Uchida
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Fomt Berger:
Gadel Talan:
Wolf Flaken:
Gol Heini:
Melda Dietz:
Yarb Skerge:
Vilki Boroz:
Cheif Rebalz:
Keel Keeling:
Ledof Hiss:
Hilde Shultz:
Koichi Yamadera
Hiroshi Kamiya
Junichi Suwabe
Kotaro Yakamura
Akimitsu Takase
Setsuji Sato
Shizuka Ito
Cho
Satoshi Taki
Takeshi Maruyama
Takahiro Mizushima
Yosuke Akimono
Ayano Miura
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Elder:
New Yamato Crewman A:
New Yamato Crewman B:
News Caster:
Barna Skerge:
Oddo Skerge:
Leeza Skerge:
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Tomohisa Aso
Hiromichi Tezuka
Hiroki Maeda
Keisuke Hamaoka
Mie Sonozaki
Tomo Muranaka
Chitose Morinaga
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru